Guide to the Brand Blanshard Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- General Files, 1915-1989; Series I; 14.25 linear feet (35 boxes)
  - Lucas, Frank Lawrence and Elna, 1969-1974, undated (Box 22, Folder 497)
  - Lyman, Richard W., 1961-1982 (Box 22, Folder 498)
  - Ma-Me (Box 22, Folder 499)
  - Mi-My (Box 22, Folder 500)
  - Mabbott, John, 1950-1960, undated (Box 22, Folder 501)
  - McAllister, Alan P., 1973 (Box 22, Folder 502)
  - McConnell, Robert A., 1974-1983 (Box 22, Folder 503)
  - McDaniel, Cecilia, 1971 (Box 22, Folder 504)
  - McGraw-Hill Book Company, 1961, 1974 (Box 22, Folder 505)
  - MacGregor, Geddes, 1962-1976 (Box 22, Folder 506)
  - Mackinnon, David M., 1957-1984, undated (Box 22, Folder 507)
  - MacLeod, Robert, 1955-1975 (Box 22, Folder 508)
  - McMaster University, 1968-1988 (Box 22, Folder 509)
  - MacMillan Company, 1940-1967 (Box 22, Folder 510-511)
  - McMurrin, Sterling M., 1962-1975 (Box 22, Folder 512)
    See also: box 32, folder 764
  - McPherson, Mary Patterson, 1978-1988 (Box 22, Folder 513)
  - Madden, Edward H., 1965-1972 (Box 22, Folder 514)
  - Malter, Barbara, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 515)
  - Manchester University Press, 1953-1983 (Box 22, Folder 516)
  - Margenau, Henry, 1948-1973 (Box 22, Folder 517)
  - Marlboro College, 1964-1981 (Box 22, Folder 518)
  - Marshall, John, 1960-1961 (Box 22, Folder 519)
  - Martin, C. B., 1986 (Box 22, Folder 520)
  - Martin, J. Arthur, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 521)
  - Marvin, Edwin, 1948-1966 (Box 22, Folder 522)
  - Matheson, Gordon W., 1954-1978, undated (Box 22, Folder 523)
  - Mayer, Gregg, 1981-1988 (Box 22, Folder 524)
  - Mayer, John R. A., 1966 (Box 23, Folder 525)
  - Mayer, Philip, 1956-1985 (Box 23, Folder 526)
  - Means, Blanchard and Louise, 1956-1979 (Box 23, Folder 527)
  - Mercier, André, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 528)
  - Merković, Mihailo, 1953-1968, undated (Box 23, Folder 529)
  - Merton College, 1961-1987 (Box 23, Folder 530)
  - Merton Society, 1981-1987 (Box 23, Folder 531)
  - Metaphysical Society of America, 1950-1977 (Box 23, Folder 532)
  - Metaphysical Society of America: annual meetings, 1951-1987 (Box 23, Folder 533)
  - Metaphysical Society of America: constitution; newsletters; announcements, 1950-1986 (Box 23, Folder 534)
  - Metaphysical Society of America: membership lists, 1963-1986 (Box 23, Folder 535)
  - Michener, James, 1984 (Box 23, Folder 536)
  - Miles, Leland, 1960-1964 (Box 23, Folder 537)
  - Miller, Dickinson S., 1941-1949 (Box 23, Folder 538)
  - Mind Association, 1942-1983 (Box 23, Folder 539)
    See also: box 22, folder 501
  - Mink, Louis, 1953-1979 (Box 23, Folder 540)
  - Mitchell, Margaret, 1959-1961 (Box 23, Folder 541)
  - Monist, 1962-1988 (Box 23, Folder 542)
  - Montague, William Pepperell, 1933-1953 (Box 23, Folder 543)
  - Moore, George Edward and Dorothy, 1920-1975 (Box 23, Folder 544)
  - Moore, Jared S., 1941-1946 (Box 23, Folder 545)
  - Moore, John M., 1943-1988 (Box 23, Folder 546)
  - Morgan, S. Rowland, 1945-1956 (Box 23, Folder 547)
  - Morrell, Mary, 1964-1988 (Box 23, Folder 548)
  - Morrow, Glenn R., 1942-1971 (Box 23, Folder 549)
  - Mottram, Eric, 1962-1963 (Box 23, Folder 550)
  - Mount Holyoke College, 1947, 1965 (Box 23, Folder 551)
  - Muirhead, J. H., 1939 (Box 23, Folder 552)
  - Mure, Geoffrey and Molly, 1940-1967, undated (Box 23, Folder 553)
  - Murphy, Arthur E., 1945-1946, 1960 (Box 23, Folder 554)
  - N (Box 24, Folder 555)
  - Nagel, Ernest, 1940-1981 (Box 24, Folder 556)
  - Naik, Ajaya D., 1977-1987 (Box 24, Folder 557)
  - Napier, Davie and Joy, 1978-1988 (Box 24, Folder 558)
    See also: box 34, folder 820
  - Nash, Aleda, 1973-1988 (Box 24, Folder 559)
  - Nason, John, 1931-1945 (Box 24, Folder 560)
  - Nason, John, 1946-1988 (Box 24, Folder 561-562)
  - Nasser, Alan G., 1963-1967 (Box 24, Folder 563)
  - Nathanson, Stephen, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 564)
  - National Portrait Gallery, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 565)
  - Nelson, Ross, 1988-1992 (Box 24, Folder 566)
  - New England College, 1981-1987 (Box 24, Folder 567)
  - New Haven Redevelopment Agency, 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 568)
  - New York Philosophy Club, 1941-1975, undated (Box 24, Folder 569)
  - Newhall, David H., 1949-1950 (Box 24, Folder 570)
  - Nicolson, Marjorie, 1933-1972 (Box 24, Folder 571)
  - Niles, Emory H., 1958-1976 (Box 24, Folder 572)
  - North American Committee for Humanism, 1982-1988 (Box 24, Folder 573)
  - Northrop, Filmer S. C., 1944-1985 (Box 24, Folder 574)
  - Norwegian Nobel Committee
    See: box 29, folder 674
  - Notestein, Wallace and Ada, 1951-1969 (Box 24, Folder 575)
  - O (Box 24, Folder 576)
  - Oakes, Robert A., 1970-1971 (Box 24, Folder 577)
  - Oberlin College, 1956-1957, 1963 (Box 24, Folder 578)
  - Odell, S. Jack, 1973-1974 (Box 24, Folder 579)
  - Ofstad, Harold, 1949-1982 (Box 24, Folder 580)
  - Open Court Publishing Company, 1959-1972 (Box 25, Folder 581)
    See also: box 23, folders 542
  - Open Court Publishing Company, 1973-1986 (Box 25, Folder 582-584)
  - Orne, Michael, 1985-1986 (Box 25, Folder 585)
  - Otto, Herbert, 1981-1988 (Box 25, Folder 586)
  - Otto, Max C., 1945 (Box 25, Folder 587)
  - Owens, Joseph, 1974-1988 (Box 25, Folder 588)
  - Pa-Pe (Box 25, Folder 589)
  - Pf-Pu (Box 25, Folder 590)
  - Paine College, 1964 (Box 25, Folder 591)
  - Palmer, S. Copeland, Jr., 1982-1988 (Box 25, Folder 592)
  - Palmer, Scott D., 1977-1988 (Box 25, Folder 593-594)
  - Pap, Arthur and Diane, 1957-1959, undated (Box 25, Folder 595)
  - Parker, DeWitt Henry, 1926-1949 (Box 25, Folder 596)
  - Parsons, Howard L., 1964-1972 (Box 25, Folder 597)
  - Pate, Martha B. Lucas, 1962-1983 (Box 26, Folder 598-599)
  - Pate Institute for Human Survival, 1983-1987 (Box 26, Folder 600)
  - Paton, H. J., 1952-1960 (Box 26, Folder 601)
  - Patrick, James, 1984 (Box 26, Folder 602)
  - Patterson, Mary, 1967-1986 (Box 26, Folder 603)
  - Patterson, Robert, 1944-1967 (Box 26, Folder 604)
  - Peacham Academy, 1946-1967, undated (Box 26, Folder 605)
  - Pederson, La Moyne, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 606)
  - Penn, Stuart, 1946, 1959-1966 (Box 26, Folder 607)
  - Pennebaker, Gregory, 1962-1965 (Box 26, Folder 608)
  - Perry, Charner, 1958, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 609)
  - Personalist Discussion Group, 1966, 1984-1987 (Box 26, Folder 610)
    See also: box 4, folders 77-78
  - Phi Beta Kappa, 1959-1965 (Box 26, Folder 611)
  - Phi Beta Kappa. Yale Chapter, 1968-1985 (Box 26, Folder 612)
  - Phillips, Winfred, 1981 (Box 26, Folder 613)
  - Philosopher's Annual, 1981-1983 (Box 26, Folder 614)
  - Phi Sigma Tau, 1962 (Box 26, Folder 615)
  - Piedmont University Center of North Carolina, 1964 (Box 26, Folder 616)
  - Pommer, Henry and Bessie, 1950-1983 (Box 26, Folder 617)
  - Porteus, Alex J. D., 1928-1932 (Box 26, Folder 618)
  - Prichard, H. A., 1929-1938 (Box 26, Folder 619)
  - Principia College, 1965-1966 (Box 26, Folder 620)
  - Q (Box 26, Folder 621)
  - Quinton, Anthony, 1984-1988 (Box 26, Folder 622)
  - Ra-Rh (Box 26, Folder 623)
  - Ri-Ry (Box 26, Folder 624)
  - Raab, Francis, 1951-1983 (Box 27, Folder 625-626)
  - Raab, Francis, 1985 (Box 27, Folder 627)
  - Raju, P. T., 1952-1964 (Box 27, Folder 628)
  - Randall, Jack H., Jr. and Mercedes, 1964-1966 (Box 27, Folder 629)
  - Raphael, David, 1955-1967 (Box 27, Folder 630)
  - Reck, Andrew J., 1952-1980 (Box 27, Folder 631)
  - Reis, Lincoln, 1953-1958 (Box 27, Folder 632)
  - Review of Metaphysics, 1964-1968, undated (Box 27, Folder 633)
  - Reynolds, Peter J., 1972 (Box 27, Folder 634)
  - Rhodes Scholarships, 1940 (Box 27, Folder 635)
  - Rhodes Scholarship Trust, 1946-1988 (Box 27, Folder 636)
  - Rice University, 1962-1973 (Box 27, Folder 637)
  - Riggs, Lawrence, 1974-1986 (Box 27, Folder 638)
  - Riise, Norman, 1979-1987 (Box 27, Folder 639)
  - Robins, Sidney, 1972-1987 (Box 27, Folder 640)
  - Robinson, Daniel S., 1945-1961 (Box 27, Folder 641)
  - Robinson, John, 1963-1988 (Box 27, Folder 642)
    See also: box 18, folder 401
  - Robinson, Richard, 1945-1946 (Box 27, Folder 643)
  - Roelofs, Howard and Miriam, 1936-1945 (Box 27, Folder 644)
  - Roelofs, Robert, 1947 (Box 27, Folder 645)
  - Rome, Sydney and Beatrice, 1956-1965 (Box 27, Folder 646)
  - Rorty, Richard and Amelie, 1961-1987 (Box 27, Folder 647)
  - Rotstain, Jake, 1980-1982 (Box 27, Folder 648)
  - Royal Institute of Philosophy, 1959-1983 (Box 27, Folder 649)
  - Russell, Bertrand, 1942, 1959 (Box 27, Folder 650)
  - Ryglewicz, Edward and Gladys, 1961-1966 (Box 27, Folder 651)
  - Ryle, Gilbert, 1949-1965 (Box 27, Folder 652)
    See also: box 23, folder 539
  - Sa-Sk (Box 27, Folder 653)
  - Sm-So (Box 28, Folder 654)
  - Sp-Sy (Box 28, Folder 655)
  - Sages Hommes, 1945, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 656)
  - Salmom, Christopher and Donna, 1946-1963 (Box 28, Folder 657)
  - Salzburg Seminar, 1953-1980 (Box 28, Folder 658)
  - Saxena, S. K, 1961-1989 (Box 28, Folder 659)
  - Schear, Sally, 1966-1988 (Box 28, Folder 660)
  - Schilpp, Paul, 1970-1976 (Box 28, Folder 661-662)
  - Schilpp, Paul, 1974-1987 (Box 28, Folder 663)
  - Schmidt, Benno, 1986-1988 (Box 28, Folder 664)
  - Schmidt, Paul, 1951-1988 (Box 28, Folder 665)
  - Schrader, George, 1947-1967 (Box 28, Folder 666)
  - Sellars, Roy, 1954, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 667)
  - Sellars, Wilfrid, 1959-1982 (Box 28, Folder 668)
  - Selzer, Lawrence and Richard, 1977-1986 (Box 28, Folder 669)
  - Sheldon, Wilmon, 1941-1975, undated (Box 28, Folder 670)
  - Sherover, Charles M., 1966, 1968 (Box 28, Folder 671)
  - Shrewsbury, Lizzie, 1917-1921 (Box 28, Folder 672)
  - Sibley, Frank, 1949-1961 (Box 28, Folder 673)
  - Silber, John, 1960-1988 (Box 29, Folder 674-676)
  - Silk, Eleanor and Edmund Taite, 1981-1988 (Box 29, Folder 677)
  - Singer, Marcus, 1983-1989 (Box 29, Folder 678)
  - Sipfle, David, 1965-1966 (Box 29, Folder 679)
  - Skinner, B. F., 1964-1966 (Box 29, Folder 680)
  - Skorpen, Erling, 1958-1974 (Box 29, Folder 681)
  - Slater, John, 1982-1988 (Box 29, Folder 682)
  - Sleeper, Ralph and Louise, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 683)
  - Slusser, John Paul, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 684)
  - Smalley, Walter B., 1960-1970 (Box 29, Folder 685)
  - Smith, Courtney, 1958-1967 (Box 29, Folder 686)
  - Smith, Esther, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 687)
  - Smith, F. Manning, 1974-1984 (Box 29, Folder 688)
  - Smith, Howard T., 1936-1967 (Box 29, Folder 689)
  - Smith, John E., 1947-1988 (Box 29, Folder 690)
  - Smith, Nancy, 1981-1982 (Box 29, Folder 691)
  - Smith College, 1949-1988 (Box 29, Folder 692)
  - Social Science Club: correspondence; membership lists, 1954-1986 (Box 29, Folder 693)
  - Social Science Club: notice of meetings, 1951-1986 (Box 29, Folder 694-697)
  - Social Science Club: photographs, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 698)
  - Society for the Philosophical Study of Dialectical Materialism, 1964-1965 (Box 30, Folder 699)
    See also: box 25, folders 597 See also: box 30, folder 701
  - Somers, Ned and Belle, 1951-1952 (Box 30, Folder 700)
  - Somerville, John, 1962-1966 (Box 30, Folder 701)
  - Sontag, Frederick, 1950-1988 (Box 30, Folder 702-703)
  - Soule, Doris
    See: box 17, folder 387
  - Southern Methodist University, 1962 (Box 30, Folder 704)
  - Southern Review, 1984-1988 (Box 30, Folder 705)
  - Spaulding, George, 1973-1982 (Box 30, Folder 706)
  - Speight, Harold, 1943-1950 (Box 30, Folder 707)
  - Sperry, Willard L., 1944-1950 (Box 30, Folder 708)
  - Spiegelberg, Herbert, 1942-1984 (Box 30, Folder 709)
  - Spiller, Robert, 1946-1975 (Box 30, Folder 710)
  - State University College at Brockport, New York, 1967-1973 (Box 30, Folder 711)
    See also: box 10, folder 206 See also: box 30, folder 713
  - State University of New York Stony Brook, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 712)
  - State University of New York Press, 1969-1970 (Box 30, Folder 713)
  - Steinkraus, Warren, 1968-1981 (Box 30, Folder 714)
  - Stichler, Richard, 1964-1988 (Box 30, Folder 715)
  - Stiernotte, Alfred, 1949-1976 (Box 30, Folder 716-718)
  - Stock, Guy, 1965-1988 (Box 30, Folder 719)
  - Stoutland, Frederick, 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 720)
  - Stringa, Marialuisa, 1952-1970 (Box 30, Folder 721)
  - Sturm, William, 1962-1963 (Box 30, Folder 722)
  - Swain, Frank G., 1974-1976 (Box 30, Folder 723)
  - Swarthmore College, 1934-1988 (Box 30, Folder 724)
    See also: box 18, folder 409 See also: box 24, folder 560
  - Swarthmore College. Honors Program, 1924-1930, undated (Box 31, Folder 725-727)
  - Swarthmore Monthly Meeting, 1928-1986, undated (Box 31, Folder 728)
  - Sylvester, Peter and Audrey, 1981-1982 (Box 31, Folder 729)
  - Syracuse University, 1967 (Box 31, Folder 730)
  - Szubka, Tadeusz, 1986-1988 (Box 31, Folder 731)
  - T (Box 31, Folder 732)
  - Tacelli, Ronald, 1971-1984 (Box 31, Folder 733)
  - Taylor, Harold, 1945-1956 (Box 31, Folder 734)
  - Taylor, Richard, 1950-1986 (Box 31, Folder 735)
  - Temple University, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 736)
  - Terrell, D. Burnham, 1946-1987 (Box 31, Folder 737)
  - Thackwell, Ross, 1965-1970 (Box 31, Folder 738)
  - Thiel College, 1961, 1973 (Box 31, Folder 739)
  - Thomas, George, 1932-1977 (Box 31, Folder 740)
  - Thomas, John, 1970-1971 (Box 31, Folder 741)
  - Tompkins, Betsy and Howard, 1966-1984, n. d. (Box 31, Folder 742)
  - Trinity College, 1958-1975 (Box 31, Folder 743)
  - Trinity College Library, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 744)
  - Turner, J. E., 1939-1944 (Box 31, Folder 745)
  - U (Box 31, Folder 746)
  - Unitarian Universalist Association: Committee on Theology and Frontiers of Learning, 1961-1963 (Box 31, Folder 747-748)
  - United States Department of the Treasury, 1940-1949, 1978 (Box 32, Folder 749)
  - United States Naval Academy, 1948-1954 (Box 32, Folder 750)
  - University Center in Virginia, 1963-1969 (Box 32, Folder 751)
  - University of Arizona, 1962-1973 (Box 32, Folder 752)
  - University of Glasgow, 1951 (Box 32, Folder 753)
  - University of Illinois, 1944-1948, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 754)
  - University of Kansas, 1953-1965 (Box 32, Folder 755)
  - University of Manchester, 1952 (Box 32, Folder 756)
  - University of Miami, 1960-1966 (Box 32, Folder 757)
  - University of Michigan, 1917-1987 (Box 32, Folder 758)
  - University of Minnesota, 1960,1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 759)
  - University of New Mexico, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 760)
  - University of Notre Dame, 1961, 1967-1968 (Box 32, Folder 761)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1948, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 762)
  - University of St. Andrews, 1950-1973 (Box 32, Folder 763)
  - University of Utah, 1965-1976 (Box 32, Folder 764)
    See also: box 22, folder 512
  - University of Wisconsin, 1975-1976, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 765)
  - Ushenko, Andrew, 1946-1947 (Box 32, Folder 766)
  - V (Box 32, Folder 767)
  - Vance, Thomas and Bennet, 1987 (Box 32, Folder 768)
  - Vander Veer, Garrett, 1959-1989 (Box 32, Folder 769-770)
  - Van Santvoord, George, 1951-1975 (Box 32, Folder 771)
  - Van Slyck, Agnes, 1919-1933 (Box 32, Folder 772)
  - Vanston, Daniel, 1968-1984 (Box 32, Folder 773)
  - Van Straaten, Zak, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 774)
  - Vassar College, 1977-1978 (Box 32, Folder 775)
  - Vivas, Eliseo, 1946-1955, 1960 (Box 32, Folder 776)
  - Wa-Wh (Box 32, Folder 777)
  - Wi-Wy (Box 32, Folder 778)
  - Wahl, Albert J., 1972-1981 (Box 33, Folder 779)
  - Wallraff, Charles F., 1952-1982 (Box 33, Folder 780)
  - Walton, W. M., 1947 (Box 33, Folder 781)
  - Warren, W. Preston, 1948-1987 (Box 33, Folder 782)
  - Washington Book Review, 1985-1986 (Box 33, Folder 783)
  - Watson, Carrie and William E., 1904-1957 (Box 33, Folder 784)
  - Watson, Ernest and Gladys, 1966-1985 (Box 33, Folder 785)
  - Webb, Clemens C. J., 1915-1951 (Box 33, Folder 786)
  - Weigand, Hermann and Mary, 1972-1987 (Box 33, Folder 787)
  - Weiss, Paul, 1935-1987 (Box 33, Folder 788)
  - Weld, Mabel, 1952-1979 (Box 33, Folder 789)
  - Wells, Carleton, 1946-1988 (Box 33, Folder 790-791)
  - Wells College, 1967-1973 (Box 33, Folder 792)
  - Wencelius, Marguerite and Leon, 1944-1945, undated (Box 33, Folder 793)
  - Wenley, R. M., 1918-1924 (Box 33, Folder 794)
  - Werkmeister, W. H., 1961-1966 (Box 33, Folder 795)
  - Wernham, A. G., 1950-1956 (Box 33, Folder 796)
  - Wesleyan University. Center for Advanced Studies, 1961-1964 (Box 33, Folder 797)
  - Wesleyan University Press, 1964-1983 (Box 33, Folder 798)
  - Wesleyan University Press: Four Reasonable Men, 1983-1986 (Box 33, Folder 799)
    See also: box 17, folder 397
  - Wesleyan University Press: Frank Aydelotte of Swarthmore, 1966-1987 (Box 33, Folder 800)
  - Wheaton College, 1966-1973 (Box 33, Folder 801)
  - Wieck, Fred, 1961-1970 (Box 33, Folder 802)
  - Wilcox, John, 1961-1969 (Box 33, Folder 803)
  - Williams, Carolyn and Samuel, 1982-1988 (Box 33, Folder 804)
  - Williams, Donald, 1943-1967 (Box 33, Folder 805)
  - Willits, Joseph, 1962, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 806)
  - Wings, Clemency Blanshard
    See: box 4, folder 88
  - Wintner, Martha, 1972-1975 (Box 33, Folder 807)
  - Wise, Kelly, 1980-1984, undated (Box 34, Folder 808)
  - Wolf, Lonn, 1975 (Box 34, Folder 809)
  - Woods, Charles, 1983-1988 (Box 34, Folder 810)
  - Wright, John N., 1954-1967 (Box 34, Folder 811)
  - Wubnig, Judith, 1957-1988 (Box 34, Folder 812)
  - Wylie, F. J. and Kathleen, 1919-1967 (Box 34, Folder 813)
  - Y (Box 34, Folder 814)
  - Yalden-Thomson, David, 1947-1950 (Box 34, Folder 815)
  - Yale Club, 1985-1986 (Box 34, Folder 816)
  - Yale Review, 1953-1982 (Box 34, Folder 817)
  - Yale University, 1944-1987 (Box 34, Folder 818-819)
  - Yale University. Calhoun College, 1949-1988 (Box 34, Folder 820)
  - Yale University. Chubb Fellowship Conference on the Work of B. F. Skinner, 1972 (Box 34, Folder 821)
  - Yale University. Department of Philosophy, 1947-1956 (Box 34, Folder 822)
    See also: box 17, folder 381 See also: box 16, folders 350
  - Yale University. Department of Philosophy, 1957-1985 (Box 34, Folder 823)
  - Yale University. Frances Bradshaw Blanshard Fellowship Fund, 1967-1986 (Box 34, Folder 824)
  - Yale University Press, 1951-1983 (Box 34, Folder 825)
  - Yerkes, David M. and Frances, 1970-1974 (Box 34, Folder 826)
  - Yerkes, David N. and Sarah, 1977-1987 (Box 34, Folder 827)
  - Yerkes, Robert M., 1946-1953, undated (Box 34, Folder 828)
  - Ylvisaker, Richard, 1963-1973 (Box 35, Folder 829)
  - Z (Box 35, Folder 830)
  - Zinsser, William, 1973-1988 (Box 35, Folder 831)
  - Zuurdeeg, William, 1947-1948 (Box 35, Folder 832)
  - Crank mail, 1937-1981, undated (Box 35, Folder 833)
  - General letters for family and friends, 1952,1974-1988 (Box 35, Folder 834)
  - Unidentified, 1918-1986, undated (Box 35, Folder 835)
  - Additional Material, 1962-1988; Accession 1995-M-114; 0.25; (1 box)
    Received from: Edward V. Lofstrom, 1995 Feb 6
    - Edward V. Lofstrom's notes on and correspondence with Brand Blanshard, 1962-1988 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
- Writing, 1913-1989; Series II; 6.5 linear feet (16 boxes)
  Material in this series is arranged by type in two sections: Manuscripts and Published copies. Manuscripts for articles and speeches are arranged at the beginning of the series in chronological order. Undated items follow those that are dated. Manuscripts for book reviews, letters to the editor, notes for talks, fragments, and book manuscripts are filed at the end of the section. Published copies of Blanshard's writings are arranged in chronological order at the end of the series.
  - Manuscripts
    - "The Connection of Metaphysics and Practice," [Oxford], Circa 1913-1920 (Box 36, Folder 1)
    - "Glastonbury": poem submitted for Newdigate Prize, 1915 (Box 36, Folder 2)
    - Oxford B. Sc. thesis, 1919-1920 (Box 36, Folder 3)
    - "The Nature of Judgement," Harvard Ph.D. Thesis, 1921 (Box 36, Folder 4)
    - [Early papers while at Michigan], Circa 1921-1925 (Box 36, Folder 5-6)
    - "The Lop -Sided Life," Wesley Hall, 1922 March 12 (Box 36, Folder 7)
    - "The Hygiene of Thought," Lane Hall, 1922 March 14 (Box 36, Folder 8)
    - "Oxford," University of Delaware dinner, 1922 March 19 (Box 36, Folder 9)
    - "Use and Abuse of Emotion," Lane Hall, 1922 March 21 (Box 36, Folder 10)
    - "Fear," Lane Hall, 1922 March 28 (Box 36, Folder 11)
    - "Will," Lane Hall, 1922 April 4 (Box 36, Folder 12)
    - "The Qualities of Men," Wesley Hall, 1922 October 1 (Box 36, Folder 13)
    - "Pitfalls of Thinking," Women's Auxiliary, Unitarian Church, 1923 April 6 (Box 36, Folder 14)
    - "Practical Values of the New Philosophy," delivered at various locations, 1923-1924 (Box 36, Folder 15)
    - "The Oratorical Mind," Delta Sigma Rho dinner, 1924 May 1 (Box 36, Folder 16)
    - "Intelligence and Its Offices," Hollins and other locations, 1925-1926 (Box 36, Folder 17)
    - "English and American Views of Honors Study," Union College, 1929 May 4 (Box 36, Folder 18)
    - "The Evolutionary Account of the Mind," Swarthmore College, Circa 1930 (Box 36, Folder 19)
    - "Values in College," Swarthmore College vesper service, 1931 March (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - "Behaviorism," Meeting House series, 1931 November 8 (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - "Courage," delivered at various locations, 1931-1956 (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - "Time," Swarthmore College vesper service, 1932 January (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - "Truth": debate with Professor Montagna, Columbia, 1932 May (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - "What are We Here For?," Swarthmore College vesper service, 1932 October 9 (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - "Are There Particulars?," American Philosophical Association, Bryn Mawr, 1932 December (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - "Scottsboro - The Story and the Issue", [ca. (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - "An Educational Odyssey," Swarthmore alumnae, 1933 May 6 (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - "Technique of Public Speaking," and notes on public speaking, 1933 December 1, undated (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - "The Inner Light," delivered at various locations, 1933-1936 (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - "The Achievement of Happiness," delivered at various locations, 1933-1937 (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - "Style," delivered at various locations, 1933-1940 (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - "What I Believe," Swarthmore College vesper service, 1934 October 7 (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - On socialism, delivered at various locations, 1934 October - November (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - "York and Dr. Jacks," Friends Intelligencer, Circa 1934 December 15 (Box 37, Folder 35)
    - "Coherence," lecture given at Bryn Mawr and Haverford, 1934-1935 (Box 37, Folder 36)
    - "Some Rules of the Game of Life," delivered at various locations, 1934-1936 (Box 37, Folder 37)
    - On philosophy: address to freshman at Swarthmore, 1934-1942 (Box 37, Folder 38)
    - "Lynching and the Law," Friends Intelligencer, Circa 1935 January 2 (Box 37, Folder 39)
    - "Meditation," Adult class, 1935 May 26 (Box 37, Folder 40)
    - On sanctions, Student Forum, 1935 October (Box 37, Folder 41)
    - "Practical Mysticism," Adult class, Swarthmore, 1935 November 24 (Box 37, Folder 43)
    - "Faith in a Changing Age," delivered at various locations, 1935-1939 (Box 37, Folder 45)
    - "Karl Marx and Communism," lecture delivered at various locations, 1935-1949 (Box 37, Folder 46)
    - "Sincerity," delivered at various locations, 1935-1954 (Box 37, Folder 47)
    - On peace methods Swarthmore, 1936 January 15 (Box 37, Folder 48)
    - "Peace," debate at Crozer Theological Seminary, 1936 January 28 (Box 37, Folder 49)
    - "Teaching," vocational study group at Swarthmore, 1936 February 14 (Box 37, Folder 50)
    - "Great Principles and Small Duties," Race St. meeting, 1936 March 24 (Box 37, Folder 51)
    - "The Relation Between Knowledge and Learning", 1936 May 6 (Box 37, Folder 52)
    - "Facts - O. G. Villard," Swarthmore, 1936 June 14 (Box 37, Folder 53)
    - "How to Study," Swarthmore, 1936 September 20 (Box 37, Folder 54)
    - Address, Quarterly meetings at West Grove, 1936 September 26 (Box 37, Folder 55)
    - "Small Quaker Meetings," West Grove, 1936 September 27 (Box 37, Folder 56)